Register of the Boutros Boutros-Ghali papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Charles Hill Advising and Projects File, 1969-2001 (Boxes 203-238)
  - Subject, policy and research file, 1969-2001 (Boxes 207-223)
    - Bosnia (former Yugoslavia)
      - Heavy weapons
        - Proposed amendments to UN Security Council Resolution 762, 1992 (Box-folder 209: 11)
      - "Implementation of the Peace Agreement for Bosnia and Herzegovina," non-paper and memorandum by Marrack Goulding, 1993 September (Box-folder 209: 12)
      - Kosovo, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 209: 13)
      - Letter from Sadako Ogata to Boutros-Ghali, 1993 February 17 (Box-folder 209: 14)
      - Pledging Conference for Sarajevo, 1994 (Box-folder 209: 15)
      - Protection of safe areas, 1994 (Box-folder 209: 16)
      - Reports and reference papers, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 209: 17)
        Includes "Bosnia: The Moment of Decision," prepared for the American Security Council Foundation and "The United Nations and the Situation in the Former Yugoslavia," reference paper published by UN Department of Public Information.
      - Reports to UN General Assembly, 1992 (Box-folder 209: 18)
      - Report to UN Security Council, 1992 October, 1995 May (Box-folder 209: 19-20)
      - Srebrenica, 1995 July (Box-folder 210: 1)
      - Statements by the Secretary General, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 210: 2)
      - Succession question, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 210: 3)
      - Summing up the policy failure, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 210: 4)
      - UN-Bosnia clippings, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 210: 5)
      - Writings by Charles Hill
        - "Bosnia in Historical Perspective," SHAFR conference, 1996 June 21 (Box-folder 210: 6)
        - "The Bosnia Debacle and What It Means,", 1993 (Box-folder 210: 7)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1995 (Box-folder 210: 8)
    - Boutros-Ghali family, biography by Arthur Goldschmidt, Jr., undated (Box-folder 210: 9)
    - Bretton Woods cooperation, undated (Box-folder 210: 10)
    - Burundi, 1996 (Box-folder 210: 11)
    - Cambodia
      - Letter from Khieu Samphan to President of the UN Security Council, 1992 July (Box-folder 210: 12)
      - Note on telephone conversation (telcon) with Yasushi Akashi, 1993 April 28 (Box-folder 210: 13)
      - Policy notes, 1993 March (Box-folder 210: 14)
      - Post-UN peacekeeping, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 210: 15)
      - Report on United Nations Transitional Authority in Cambodia (UNTAC), 1995 (Box-folder 210: 16-17)
      - UN press release, 1993 (Box-folder 210: 18)
      - "The United Nations and Cambodia: October 1991-September 1993," draft manuscript, 1994 (Box-folder 210: 19)
    - Carnegie Commission on Preventing the Deadliest Conflicts, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 211: 1)
    - Climate change, 1995 (Box-folder 211: 2)
    - Confederation of Independent States (CIS) legal status, 1996 (Box-folder 211: 3)
    - Conferences
      - General, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 211: 4)
      - Bosnia Peace Implementation Conference, 1995 December 8-9 (Box-folder 211: 5)
      - Costs of women's conferences, 1996 (Box-folder 211: 6)
      - Habitat II, Istanbul, Turkey, list on non-governmental organizations, 1996 (Box-folder 211: 7)
      - International Conference on the Former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (London Conference), 1992 (Box-folder 211: 8-9)
        Includes original notes of Boutros Boutros-Ghali.
      - International Conference on the Former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (London Conference), 1995 (Box-folder 211: 10)
      - Islamic Conference of Foreign Ministers (ICFM), 1993 (Box-folder 211: 11)
      - Organization of the Islamic Conference, 1993 (Box-folder 211: 12)
      - United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED), Brazil, 1992 May
        - Program and list of attendees, 1992 (Box-folder 211: 13)
        - Follow up reports and notes, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 211: 14)
        - Transcript of meeting with President Bush, 1992 May (Box-folder 211: 15)
      - Population Conference (UNFPA), 1993 (Box-folder 211: 16-17)
    - Cyprus
      - General, 1992 (Box-folder 211: 18)
      - United Nations Peace-keeping Forces in Cyprus (UNFICYP) finances, 1996 (Box-folder 211: 19)
    - Democracy and the United Nations, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 211: 20)
    - Democratization, assistance to, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 211: 21)
    - Department of State, Digest of International Law, Vol. 13, "Appointment of Secretary General" (Box-folder 211: 22)
    - Disarmament (Box-folder 211: 23)
    - Disarmament Week, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 211: 24)
    - Egypt
      - Apartheid, 1994 (Box-folder 211: 25)
      - "The Foreign Policy of Egypt," by Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 1963 (Box-folder 211: 26)
      - Minutes of meeting between representatives of the National Democratic Party of Egypt and the Israeli Labour Party, Cairo, 1980 November 7 (Box-folder 211: 27)
      - Positions on West Bank/Gaza, 1979-1980, report, 1981 (Box-folder 212: 1)
    - El Salvador, notes on Boutros-Ghali's statements to Charles Hill, 1997 (Box-folder 212: 2)
    - Ethnic conflicts, 1993 (Box-folder 212: 3-4)
    - Ethnicity and the state, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 212: 5)
    - Fiji, 1995 (Box-folder 212: 6)
    - France and Africa, 1996 (Box-folder 212: 7)
    - Genocide, 1994 (Box-folder 212: 8)
    - George C. Marshall International Center, 1993 (Box-folder 212: 9)
    - Georgia, disputed UNOMIG letters, 1994 (Box-folder 212: 10)
    - German, Erik, research paper on Boutros Boutros-Ghali and related research materials, 1996 (Box-folder 212: 11)
    - Group of 77, newsletter, 1996 (Box-folder 212: 12)
    - Guatemala, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 212: 13)
    - Haiti, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 212: 14-15)
    - Halifax (G-7) economic summit, 1995 (Box-folder 212: 16)
    - Hannay, David, "Recent Trends in UN Peacekeeping,", 1993 April (Box-folder 212: 17)
    - Hartley, Glenn, undated (Box-folder 212: 18)
    - Hodson, Randy et. al., "National Tolerance in Yugoslavia,", 1992 (Box-folder 212: 19)
    - House of Commons Foreign Affairs Committee reports on the expanding role of the United Nations and effect on British policy, 1993 (Box-folder 213: 1)
    - Hudson, Richard (Center for War/Peace Studies), 1993 (Box-folder 213: 2)
    - Human rights, 1993-1997
      - General, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 213: 3-4)
      - UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, 1993 (Box-folder 213: 5)
      - World Conference on Human Rights, 1993 (Box-folder 213: 6)
    - Humanitarian Affairs, Jonah/Ellison drafts, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 213: 7)
    - International Civil Service, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 213: 8)
    - International Court of Justice, The Hague, 1992 (Box-folder 213: 9)
    - International Republican Institute (IRI) National Convention, 1996 (Box-folder 213: 10)
    - International Tribunal for the Law of the Sea. Briefing book and related reports, 1996 (Box-folder 213: 11-13)
      See also: Subject File/Law of the Sea.
    - International Week of Science and Peace, 1992 (Box-folder 214: 1)
    - Israel and the UN, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 2)
    - Japan
      - United Nations relations, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 3-4)
      - Debate after secretary general's visit, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 5)
    - Jerusalem tunnel, 1996 (Box-folder 214: 6)
    - Judicial review and the UN, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 7)
    - Kashmir, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 8)
    - Land mines
      - International Meeting on Mine Clearance, 1995 (Box-folder 214: 9)
      - "The Global Mine Crisis,", 1994 (Box-folder 214: 10)
      - Land mine conference controversy, 1996 (Box-folder 214: 11)
    - Libya
      See also: Secretary-General of the United Nations File/Geographical files/Libya.
      - Chronology of events, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 214: 12)
      - Clippings on Pan Am 103, 1996 (Box-folder 214: 13)
      - William C. Gilmore letter to Lord Trefgarne, 1994 May 19 (Box-folder 214: 14)
      - Minutes of the meeting between Qaddafi and Petrovsky, 1992 May 11 (Box-folder 214: 15)
      - UN Security Council resolutions, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 214: 16)
    - Lyons Summit, 1996 (Box-folder 214: 17)
    - Macedonia
      - Clippings, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 214: 18)
      - Name negotiations, 1996 July (Box-folder 214: 19)
    - Middle East
      - Armed forces, 1996 (Box-folder 215: 1)
      - Deportation of Palestinians, 1992 December-1993 February (Box-folder 215: 2-3)
        Includes documents given to Ambassador Gharekhan.
      - Israeli-Palestinian peace process and post-Madrid autonomy negotiations - "Riverbed" project, 1986-1993 (Box-folder 215: 4-8)
        Includes correspondence, writings and notes of Gidon Gottlieb.
      - Situation in the Middle East (Palestine), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 215: 9)
        UN General Assembly documents.
    - Non-governmental organizations (NGOs), 1995 (Box-folder 215: 10)
      Includes speeches by Boutros-Ghali.
    - Non-proliferation treaty renewal, 1995 April (Box-folder 215: 11)
    - Nordenfelt, John, "The Role of Arms Limitation and Disarmament in the Promotion of Collective Security under the Charter of the United Nations,", 1992 March (Box-folder 216: 1)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), note, 1993 (Box-folder 216: 2)
    - North Korea (Democratic People's Republic of Korea) nuclear issue, 1993-1994
      Includes briefings, talking points, clippings, notes, and assessments.
      - General, 1994 (Box-folder 216: 3)
      - Briefing for Charles Hill by Allan Romberg and Richard Solomon, 1993 December 13 (Box-folder 216: 4)
      - Proliferation, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 216: 5)
      - Talking points for the Secretary General (Box-folder 216: 6)
      - Weapons, 1993 (Box-folder 216: 7)
    - Onassis Foundation Award, 1995 (Box-folder 216: 8)
    - Organization for African Unity (OAU) summit, Yaounde, Cameroon, 1996 (Box-folder 216: 9)
    - Park, Tongsun, notes of Charles Hill (Box-folder 216: 10)
    - Peace-building, 1993 (Box-folder 216: 11)
    - Peacemaking/peace-keeping, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 216: 12-13)
    - Picco, Giandomenico, Foreign Affairs article, 1994 (Box-folder 216: 14)
    - Policy planning unit, notes, 1993 (Box-folder 216: 15)
    - Preventive diplomacy, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 216: 16-18)
    - Qana, 1996 April (Box-folder 216: 19)
    - Re-election campaign
      Includes clippings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, and reports relating to the Secretary General of the United Nations' 1996 re-election campaign and the U.S. decision to veto his re-election.
      - Compiled clippings, statements, briefings, and correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 217: 1-5)
      - Statement by Senator Paul Simon, 1996 (Box-folder 217: 6)
      - Letter, 1996 (Box-folder 217: 7)
        Originally labeled "Last ditch letter."
      - Clippings on U.S.-U.N. relationship and re-election campaign, 1996 (Box-folder 217: 8, Box-folder 218: 1-2)
      - Compilation of references in statements on the 51st session of the General Assembly, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 3)
      - Talking points (draft), 1996 (Box-folder 218: 4)
      - Writings and correspondence of the Executive Office of the Secretary General (EOSG), 1996 (Box-folder 218: 5)
    - Reed, Joseph Verner
      - Letter from Thomas Eagleton to George Shultz, letter from Georgie Anne Geyer to Reed, and statement by Reed, 1982, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 6)
      - Letter from Georgie Anne Geyer to Reed, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 7)
        On U.S. campaign against Boutros-Ghali.
      - Speech, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 8)
    - Reform of United Nations, 1992-1995
      - General, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 218: 9)
      - "Reforme + Suivi de Rio,", 1992 October-November (Box-folder 218: 10)
        Contains mostly minutes from meetings in 1992.
      - Note to United Nations General Assembly, 1992 (Box-folder 218: 11)
      - Reform measures by Boutros-Ghali, 1992 (Box-folder 218: 12)
      - Attempt to merge women's groups, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 218: 13)
      - Clippings, 1995 (Box-folder 218: 14)
      - U.S. non-paper, "Readying the United Nations for the Twenty-First Century,", 1995 (Box-folder 218: 15)
      - Talking points for G-7 summit, 1996 June 29 (Box-folder 218: 16)
      - Notes and memoranda, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 17)
    - Regionalism (Somalia and former Yugoslavia), 1992-1993 (Box-folder 219: 1)
    - Reorganization of the DPA-DPKO, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 219: 2)
    - Restructuring the secretariat, notes, memoranda, and clippings, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 219: 3)
    - Review of 1993, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 4)
    - Russett, Bruce, quotes for publication, 2000 (Box-folder 219: 5)
    - Russia
      - The second coup, policy notes and clippings, 1993 September-October (Box-folder 219: 6)
      - Spheres of influence, notes, speech, and clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 7)
        Includes statement by Boris Yeltsin before the general assembly of the United Nations, September 26, 1994.
    - Rwanda
      See also: Secretary General of the United Nations File/Geographical file/Rwanda I and II.
      - Chronology of events, 1995 (Box-folder 219: 8)
      - Clippings, cables, and other documents, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 9-10)
      - Articles and notes, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 11)
      - "Preliminary Report of the Independent Commission of Experts Established in Accordance with Security Council Resolution 935 (1994),", 1994 September 29 (Box-folder 219: 12)
      - Genocide, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 13)
      - Genocide controversy (Dallaire-Baril), 1994 January (Box-folder 219: 14)
        Includes notes of Charles Hill.
      - Non-paper on possible UNAMIR future mandate, 1994 May (Box-folder 219: 15)
      - Security in refugee camps, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 16)
      - U.S. talking points, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 17)
    - Safe havens, 1996 (Box-folder 219: 18)
    - Sanjuan, Pedro, letters to the editor of the Wall Street Journal by Boutros-Ghali regarding article by Pedro Sanjuan, 1996 (Box-folder 219: 19)
    - "Saving Failed States" by Gerald B. Helman and Steven R. Ratner, 1993 (Box-folder 219: 20)
    - Serbia sanctions, 1994 (Box-folder 219: 21)
    - Shen Tong, statement by Secretary General at UNCA Club, 1993 (Box-folder 219: 22)
    - Sills, Joe, answers to anti-UN charges, 1996 (Box-folder 219: 23)
    - Slavery, statement by H.E. Razali Ismail to commemorate the International Day for the Abolition of Slavery, 1996 December (Box-folder 219: 24)
    - Somalia, 1992-1994
      - General, 1992 (Box-folder 220: 1-2)
      - Clippings and notes
        - 1992 (Box-folder 220: 3)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 220: 4-5)
        - 1994 (Box-folder 220: 6)
      - Final report of Ambassador Sahnoun, 1992 October 12 (Box-folder 220: 7)
      - Howe, Jonathan T., letter to the Secretary General, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 8)
      - "The Lost History of U.S. Incompetence," memorandum by Charles Hill, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 9)
      - Meeting notes, 1993
        - General, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 10)
        - Key documents, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 11)
          Includes original memorandum from Madeleine Albright
        - Notes from meeting with Madeleine Albright, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 12)
        - Notes from meeting with Warren Christopher, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 13)
        - Notes from meeting with President Bill Clinton, 1993 September 27 (Box-folder 220: 14)
      - Peacekeeping, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 15)
      - Talking points for UN Security Council, 1993 October 6 (Box-folder 220: 16)
      - UN Security Council Resolution 814 and 865, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 17)
    - Sorenson, Gillian, notes, 1996 (Box-folder 220: 18)
    - Standby troops ("master plan"), 1993 January (Box-folder 220: 19)
    - Strong, Maurice, Charles Hill memorandum criticizing draft of reform speech, 1996 (Box-folder 220: 20)
    - Sudan, letter from Boutros-Ghali to the Christian Association of Upper Egypt, 1993 February 5 (Box-folder 220: 21)
    - Syria and Golan Heights, 1993 (Box-folder 220: 22)
    - "The Technology Frontier: Responses to Environmental Challenges" by Nazli Choucri, 1991 (Box-folder 220: 23)
    - Terrorism, 1996 (Box-folder 220: 24)
    - United Nations
      - General
        - General, 1996 (Box-folder 221: 1)
        - Organizational chart, 1990 (Box-folder 221: 2)
        - Telephone directories (Box-folder 221: 3-4)
      - Appointment of the UN Secretary General, Digest of International Law, vol. 13, 1996 (Box-folder 221: 5)
      - Charter
        - General, undated (Box-folder 221: 6)
        - Covenant of the League of Nations, undated (Box-folder 221: 7)
        - Interpretations (Box-folder 221: 8)
      - Economic and Social Council, 1993 (Box-folder 221: 9)
      - Environmental issues, 1992 (Box-folder 221: 10)
      - Executive Office of the Secretary General
        - General, undated (Box-folder 221: 11)
        - Organizational chart, undated (Box-folder 221: 12)
      - Fiftieth anniversary
        - General, 1995 (Box-folder 221: 13)
        - Commentaries, 1995 (Box-folder 221: 14)
        - Event packet (Box-folder 221: 15)
        - Kurt Waldheim correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 221: 16)
        - Origins, 1944, 1992 (Box-folder 221: 17)
        - Printed materials, 1995 (Box-folder 222: 1-2)
        - Themes, 1994 (Box-folder 222: 3)
        - UNA/USA request for money, 1996 (Box-folder 222: 4)
        - Yearbook (memoradum), 1995 (Box-folder 222: 5)
      - Peacekeeping, "Authorizing an ad-hoc multinational force,", 1994 (Box-folder 222: 6)
      - Regional associations and agencies, 1992 (Box-folder 222: 7)
      - Speeches and statements, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 222: 8)
      - "The Third World," The Economist, 1989 September 23 (Box-folder 222: 9)
      - UNICEF, decision on new director, 1995 January (Box-folder 222: 10)
      - Volunteer force, letter to New York Review of Books, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 11)
    - United States-United Nations relations
      - Clinton administration foreign policy and policy towards UN, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 222: 12)
      - Financial crisis, 1996 (Box-folder 222: 13)
      - Legislation attacking UN, 1995 (Box-folder 222: 14)
      - Notes of Charles Hill (Box-folder 222: 15)
      - Peacekeeping, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 222: 16-17)
      - Promotion of democracy, 1995 (Box-folder 222: 18)
    - Uti Possidetis, 1995 (Box-folder 222: 19)
    - Uti Possidetis Juris (Organization of African Unity), 1969, undated (Box-folder 222: 20)
    - "Visions of a Better World" foreword, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 21)
    - War crimes, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 22)
    - Washburn, John, undated (Box-folder 222: 23)
    - Women, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 24)
    - World conflicts and casualties, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 25)
    - World economy, 1992 (Box-folder 222: 26)
    - World Summit for Social Development, 1993 (Box-folder 222: 27)
    - Yale University
      - General, 1997 (Box-folder 223: 1)
      - Visit by the Secretary General, 1995 (Box-folder 223: 2)
      - UN teaching documents, 1992 (Box-folder 223: 3)
      - Yale University-Ford Foundation report on UN reform and budget, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 223: 4)
    - Zuckerman, Mort, article and response, 1996 May (Box-folder 223: 5)
  - Talking points
    - UN financial situation, undated (Box-folder 223: 6)
    - Joint meeting of Senate and Sejm Foreign Affairs Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 223: 7)
    - U.S. Commission to Improve the Effectiveness of the UN, 1993 (Box-folder 223: 8)
    - OAU Summit, Yaounde, Cameroon, 1996 July (Box-folder 223: 9)
  - Travel invoices and miscellaneous correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 223: 10-13)
    Relates in part to Charles Hill's activities on the board of Maxtor Corporation. Includes some correspondence regarding speaking events.
  - Writings
    - "Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", undated (Box-folder 223: 14)
    - "UN and Antropology,", 1992 December 10 (Box-folder 223: 15)
    - "Why the U.S. Needs the UN,", 1993 January-February (Box-folder 223: 16-17)
    - "What is the UN?,", 1994 March 24 (Box-folder 223: 18)
    - "The U.S. and the UN: How Not to Be a Superpower,", 1995 February (Box-folder 223: 19)
    - "The UN in Crisis,", 1996 (Box-folder 223: 20)
    - "Why Does the U.S. Want Boutros-Ghali to Go?,", 1996 June 12 (Box-folder 223: 21)
  - Papers of the United Nations Secretary General, Boutros Boutros-Ghali (Yale University Press) (Boxes 224-238)
    - General, project funding, background, and advisory board, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 224: 1-2)
    - Correspondence of the Secretary-General, geographically arranged
      Photocopies.
      - Chronology of correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 224: 3)
      - Algeria, 1995 (Box-folder 224: 4)
      - Angola, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 224: 5-7)
      - Armenia, 1993 (Box-folder 224: 8)
      - Bosnia (former Yugoslavia), 1992 (Box-folder 224: 9)
      - Burundi, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 224: 10-11)
      - Cambodia, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 224: 12-13)
      - Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS), 1993 (Box-folder 224: 14)
      - Croatia, 1995 (Box-folder 224: 15)
      - East Timor, 1994 (Box-folder 224: 16)
      - El Salvador, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 224: 17-18)
      - Eritrea, 1992, 1996 (Box-folder 224: 19-20)
      - Ethiopia, 1994 (Box-folder 224: 21)
      - France, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 1)
      - Georgia, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 2)
      - Ghana and Togo, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 225: 3-4)
      - Guinea, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 5)
      - Haiti, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 225: 6-8)
      - Israel, 1996 (Box-folder 225: 9)
      - Jordan, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 10)
      - Liberia, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 225: 11-13)
      - Libya, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 225: 14-15)
        Includes Libya-Chad.
      - Malawi, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 16)
      - Malaysia, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 17)
      - Moldova, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 18)
      - Mozambique, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 225: 19-21)
      - Nicaragua, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 22)
      - Nigeria, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 23)
      - Pakistan, 1995 (Box-folder 225: 24)
      - Portugal, 1996 (Box-folder 225: 25)
      - Russia, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 225: 26-27)
      - Rwanda, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 225: 28-31)
      - Senegal, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 32)
      - Sierra Leone, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 33)
      - Somalia, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 225: 34-36)
      - South Africa, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 225: 37-38)
      - Sudan, 1992, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 39)
      - Tajikistan, 1994 (Box-folder 225: 40)
      - Turkmenistan, 1996 (Box-folder 225: 41)
      - United Kingdom (Box-folder 225: 42)
      - Western Sahara, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 225: 43)
      - Zaire, 1993 (Box-folder 225: 44)
      - Zambia, 1996 (Box-folder 225: 45)
    - Research materials
      - Documents used
        Contains speeches, writings, correspondence, press releases, and reports. Originals and photocopies.
        - English
          - Undated (Box-folder 225: 46)
          - 1992 January-December (Box-folder 225: 47-50, Box-folder 226: 1-8)
          - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 226: 9-10)
          - 1993 January-December (Box-folder 227: 1-12)
          - 1994 January-December (Box-folder 227: 13, Box-folder 228: 1-11)
          - 1995 January-December (Box-folder 228: 12-14, Box-folder 229: 1-9)
          - 1996 January-December (Box-folder 229: 10-16, Box-folder 230: 1-5)
        - Arabic, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 230: 6)
        - French, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 230: 7-11)
      - Documents not used ("outtakes")
        - 1991 (Box-folder 230: 12)
        - 1992 (Box-folder 231: 1)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 231: 2)
        - 1994 (Box-folder 231: 3)
        - 1995 (Box-folder 231: 4)
        - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 231: 5)
        - 1996 (Box-folder 231: 6)
      - Chronology of events (1992-1996), 2000 (Box-folder 231: 7)
      - Extras, 1996 (Box-folder 231: 8)
        Typed letters printed from electronic document.
      - Miscellaneous, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 231: 9, Box-folder 232: 1)
        Original label: "Letters We Want But Don't Have."
      - Lists of blue books and requests for documents, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 232: 2-4)